嗨  帮我个忙  去七号桌点菜吧
Hey, do me a favor and take Table Seven.
你是说有我那个118磅重的
tiger rabbit zoos chamazee You mean the one with my 118-pound
性欲旺盛的最近可能得了
rock-hard stud of a fiance
口腔溃疡和红眼病的未婚夫的那桌吗
dort dort dort who's prone to canker sores and pinkeye?
不对  我更愿意看作是有我的前男友
Nah, I prefer to look at it as the one with my ex-boyfriend
和她那美丽成功而知性的女友的那桌
and his gorgeous, successful and sophisticated girlfriend,
那女孩让我觉得自己就像个没用的乡巴佬
who makes me feel like a toothless Okie.
你想让我往她身上洒热汤吗
Do you want me to spill hot soup on her?
拜托  你不是那种人
Oh, please-- you're not that kind of person.
我知道
I know.
但如果她点了低脂食物的话
But if she orders something low-fat
我绝对可以给她端上全脂的
I'll totally give her the full-fat version.
这杯水是我的
Uh, that's my water.
什么
What?
我的水  你喝的是我的水
My water. You're drinking it.
苍天啊
D-Dear Lord!
你喝过吗
Have you been drinking it?
肯定啊  都说了是我的水了
Yes. It's my water.
那完蛋了
Well, that's it then.
我死翘翘了
I'm dead.
又来了
Here we go...
不好意思  但非得让我把话挑明了吗
I'm sorry, do I really need to connect the dots for you?
流回到这个杯子里的
The backwash into this glass
是在你那所谓温暖的家的嘴里待过的每一个病原体
is every pathogen that calls your mouth home, sweet home.
更别提那些来自你那次大陆女友的
Not to mention the visitors who arrive on the dancing tongue
舌头上的外来病原体了
of your subtropical girlfriend.
喂  你这是在诋毁
Hey! That's my sister
我妹妹和我的祖国
and my country you're talking about.
莱纳德也许玷污了其中一个
Leonard may have defiled one,
但我绝对不允许你再侮辱另外一个
but I won't have you talking smack about the other.
你们准备好点菜了吗
You guys ready to order?
准备好了  我要七天疗程的青霉素
Yes, I'd like a seven-day course of penicillin,
一定量的吐根糖浆  催吐用的
some, uh, syrup of ipecac-- to induce vomiting.
再来颗薄荷糖
and a mint.
我没听明白
I don't understand.
他喝了莱纳德杯子里的水
He drank from Leonard's glass.
"他喝了莱纳德杯子里的水"
"He drank from Leonard's glass"--
这句话得刻在我的墓碑上
the words they'll be carving into my tombstone.
这餐巾其实也是我的
That's actually my napkin.
坑死爹了
Oh, this is a nightmare!
-你要去哪儿  -去酒吧
- Where are you going? - To the bar,
用酒精给口腔消毒
to sterilize my mouth with alcohol.
快让开  行尸走肉来了
Gang way! Dead man walking!
生活大爆炸
第四季第二十三集
好的  拿好了
All right. Here you go.
两杯柠檬汽水
Two lemonades,
一杯冰茶
one iced tea
还有普丽娅的一杯根汁汽水
and a root beer for Priya.
-是无糖的吗  -这就是你点的
- Is it diet? - That's what you ordered.
谢谢
Thank you.
嗨  你和霍华德
Hey, have you and Howard
开始计划婚礼了吗
started planning your wedding yet?
嗯  我们想在一个能俯视大海的
Yeah. We're thinking of having it on a cliff
悬崖上办婚礼
overlooking the ocean.
没什么能比担心摔下去溺死
Nothing soothes those pre-wedding jitters
更能缓解婚礼前的紧张了
like the thought of falling and drowning.
你跟你妈妈说
What did your mother say
你俩要结婚的时候  她说啥了吗
when you told her you were getting married?
他还没跟他妈妈说
He hasn't told her yet.
他在等合适的时机
He's waiting for the right time.
其实我想把这事儿编进悼词里
I was thinking of weaving it into her eulogy.
霍华德  你必须告诉你妈妈
Howard, you've got to tell your mother.
喂  你跟你爸妈说了你在
Hey, have you told your parents you're dating
跟这一小杯"脱脂牛奶"约会吗
this short glass of skim milk here?
呃  这不一样
Uh... that's different.
首先  我们还没订婚
First of all, we're not engaged;
其次  印度父母
and second, Indian parents
都对孩子很不放心的
are very protective of their children.
是啊是啊  而犹太母亲
Right, right, whereas Jewish mothers
一般都任自己的儿子自生自灭的
take a casual, la-di-da approach to their sons.
我在用龙舌兰酒漱口的时候貌似咽下了一点点
I gargled with tequila and may have swallowed a teeny bit.
-你没事吧  -没事
- You all right? - Fine.
多谢关心
Thank you for asking.
我好爱你哦
I love you so much.
火魔
Fire demon.
哇  火魔
Ooh, fire demon.
谢尔顿开始引爆游戏热度了
Sheldon's turning up the heat...
巨怪首领
Troll master.
看啊  霍华德从流氓团伙里
Check it! Howard pulls one out
拽出了一只巨怪首领  漂亮
from under the bridge. Nice!
水仙女
Water nymph.
哦也  她的"那个地方"
Oh, yeah, she's got puddles
充满了粘液
in all the right places.
劳驾您能在打牌的时候
Could you please play the game
别老是打一张解说一句吗
without commenting on every card?
抱歉
Sorry.
树怪
Walking tree.
下不为例
Last one.
我是运动的树  我在散步
I'm taking a stroll and I'm sporting wood.
好吧  终于还是发生了
Okay, the Eagle has landed.
怎么了
What's going on?
伯纳黛特和我妈妈正在
Bernadette and my mother are having
老镇餐厅第一次共进午餐
a get-to-know-you lunch at the Old Town Deli.
听起来不错啊
Oh, that sounds lovely.
但愿如此
Hope so.
当然  根据以往的经验
Of course, if history is any indication,
我老妈会把她囫囵吞了
my mother will swallow her whole
然后像猫头鹰一样把骨头吐出来
and spit out her bones like an owl.
你见过伯纳黛特的父母了吗
Have you met Bernadette's parents?
你是说希特勒和爱娃吗
You mean Adolf and Eva?
还没呢
Not yet.
一步一步来嘛
One goose step at a time.
谢尔顿  这杯水是我的
Sheldon, that's my water.
苍天啊
Oh, dear Lord!
那杯水不是你的
That's not your water.
我知道
I know.
我的漱口液在哪儿呢
Where's the mouthwash?!
在哪儿呢
"Where" indeed.
妈  我回来了
Ma, I'm home!
你在哪
Where are you?
我在厕所
I'm in the toilet!
进行得怎么样
So, how'd it go?!
现在还说不准呢
Too soon to say!
我还没拉完呢
I'm not done yet!
我是说你跟伯纳黛特的午饭吃的怎么样
No, I mean lunch, today, with Bernadette!
我吃了个五香熏肉三明治
I had a pastrami sandwich.
她吃了个茄子肉酱千层面
She had eggplant lasagna.
就好像在犹太餐馆就该点这种东西吃
Like that's what a person orders in a Jewish deli.
除了吃的以外呢  你们相处得怎么样
Besides food, did you get along?
你们聊天了吗
Did you talk?
当然了  你知道吗
Oh, sure! Did you know she's going to school
她正在读微生物学呢
to become a microbiologist?!
不知道  她还真没提过
No, she never mentioned it.
她肯定提过  是你没注意听
I bet she did and you didn't listen!
没准吧  那你觉得她怎么样
Yeah, that's probably it. So, what do you think?
你喜欢她吗  她是个好女孩对吧
Do you like her? She's great, huh?
她是个挺可爱的
She's a lovely girl!
超级可爱
Cute as a button!
听你这么说我就放心了  因为我有事要跟你说
That's good to hear, 'cause I've got some news.
最好是好事
I hope it's good news,
因为我在厕所里进展可不怎么样  都快郁闷死了
because I've got nothing but disappointment in here!
我要跟伯纳黛特结婚了
Bernadette and I are getting married.
妈
Ma?
你正忙着使劲呢吗
You too busy bearing down?
妈
Ma?
天啊  妈  妈  妈
Oh, my God, Ma? Ma? Ma?
退后点  我要撞门了
Stand back, I'm gonna break the door down!
该死的  妈  救我
Son of a bitch! Ma, help!
你好
Hello.
好久不见了
Haven't seen you in a while.
你最近咋样啊
How's it going?
除了等着那些致命的有机物
Oh, other than waiting out the exponential growth period
沿着我的绒毛组织
of the virulent organisms
侵入我的血液循环系统外
trooping through my microvilli
就没啥特别的了
into my circulatory system -- hunky-dory.
很好笑吗
Did I say something amusing?
不知道  也许吧  我完全没听懂你在说什么
I don't know, maybe, I have no idea what you said.
这么说你刚才的欢笑声只是为了释放你的紧张情绪
So your mirth is merely a discharge of nervous energy
没有任何实际意义咯
with no semantic content at all?
我的欢笑声  还真是谢尔顿的经典语录啊
My mirth. Classic.
我啥时候才能理解
Is there a station coming up
你这些奇怪的笑声呀
where I can board your giggling train of thought?
这没啥大不了的  谢尔顿
It's not a big deal, Sheldon.
只是  自从莱纳德跟拉杰的妹妹在一起之后
It's just, ever since Leonard's been dating Raj's sister,
我就得跟你们保持距离了
I've had to keep my distance.
我就没机会听你的这些胡言乱语了
I don't get to hear all your jibber-jabber.
胡言乱语
Jibber-jabber?!
我才不会胡言乱语呢
I don't jibber-jabber.
你这段时间上班都忙什么呢
What are you doing at work these days?
我在研究弦理论的
Oh, I'm working on time-dependent backgrounds
时间依赖性
in string theory,
尤其是量子场论
specifically quantum field theory
在德西特时空d维空间中的应用
in "d-dimensional" de Sitter space.
拜托  这下你总得承认那是胡言乱语了吧
Okay, come on, even you have to admit that's jibber-jabber.
有意思  你知不知道
Interesting, do you know
胡言乱语这个词是怎么来的
where the phrase "jibber-jabber" comes from?
天啊  你就要说一堆关于胡言乱语的
Oh, my God, you're about to jibber-jabber
胡言乱语了
about jibber-jabber.
霍华德和他妈进医院了
Howard and his mother are at the hospital.
-快点  咱们走  -天啊  出什么事了
- Come on, we gotta go.  - Oh, my God! What happened?
不知道  我只是收到短信而已  快点  快走
I don't know, I just got a text. Come on, hurry.
好吧
Okay.
谢尔顿  走啦
Sheldon, let's go!
去医院吗
To a hospital?!
那个满是病人的地方
Full of sick people?!
我才不去呢
Oh, I don't think so.
你朋友和他母亲都进医院了
Okay, well, your friend and his mother are there,
你非去不可
we're going.
我不要
I can't.
别跟我说你怕细菌啊
Oh, don't tell me you're afraid of germs.
不是所有的细菌
Not all germs.
我只怕那些会让我病死的细菌
Just the ones that will kill me.
就像是我并不是害怕所有的餐刀
It's the same way I'm not afraid of all steak knives --
我只怕那些会捅死我的餐刀
just the ones that might be plunged in my thorax.
好吧  那我就跟霍华德说
Fine, I'll tell Howard you didn't come
你没去医院是因为比起他的健康
because you're more concerned
你更担心你自己的身体
about your own well-being than his.
我想他是很清楚这一点的
I would think he would know that.
好吧  算了吧  你简直不可理喻
Okay, you know what? You are unbelievable.
你买了那么多超级英雄的恤衫
You buy all these superhero T-shirts,
可是到了你该挺身而出
but when it's time for you
做点正确的事的时候
to step up and do the right thing,
你就只会躲在洗衣房里
you just hide in the laundry room.
好吧  我去就是了
Fine, I'll go.
不过事先声明
Just for the record,
我的舅妈露丝就是死在医院里的
my Aunt Ruth died in a hospital.
她去医院探望我舅舅罗杰
She went in to visit my Uncle Roger,
结果却染上了病  结果一周后就挂了
caught something and bit the dust a week later.
他俩现在都被装在我妈壁炉架上的
The two of them now share a coffee can
同一个咖啡罐里
on my mother's mantel.
于是我撞开了洗手间的门
So I knocked down the bathroom door,
抬起我那不省人事的母亲
picked up my poor unconscious mother,
把她抱上车
carried her to the car,
然后像个疯子一样开来了急诊室
and drove like a madman to the emergency room.
你真是个英雄  霍华德
You're a real hero, Howard.
不  我只是尽了一个儿子应尽的义务而已
No, I did what any son would do.
等一下  你抱起了你母亲
Hang on a second -- you picked up your mother?
她的体重连她自己的双腿都支撑不住
Her own legs are barely able to do that.
都是肾上腺素的作用
I was filled with adrenaline.
就像是母亲为了救出车下的婴儿  可以把车抬起来一样
It happens to be how women lift cars off babies.
我就是这个意思  抬车都比抬你妈容易
Yeah, I'm saying, it'd be easier to lift a car.
怎么说呢  在我鼓足了勇气
What can I tell you? After I found the courage
提上她的裤子之后  人类就阻挡不了我了
to put her pants back on, I was unstoppable.
你妈妈现在怎样
So, how is she?
还在作检查  我不知道
They're running tests-- I don't know.
可能是心脏病发作或类似心脏病发作
It may have been a heart attack or heart-attack-like event.
有何区别
What's the difference?
类似心脏病发作
A heart-attack-like event
就是指类似发作心脏病的症状
is an event that's like a heart attack.
谢谢说明
Thanks for clearing that up.
当然  冠状心脏疾患是可治的
Regardless, coronary problems are eminently treatable.
真正害死霍华德妈妈的
What's more likely going to kill Howard's mother
是在这医院每条沟沟壑壑里
are the antibiotic-resistant super-bugs
溃烂着的耐抗生素的超级臭虫们
festering in every nook and cranny of this hospital.
拜托  你别添乱了
Okay, you're not helping.
我不同意
Disagree.
去  那边坐着去
Go sit over there.
我要坐那里   看着更干净
I'll sit over there-- it looks cleaner.
你们家族有心脏病史吗
Is there a history of heart disease in your family?
我的家族史  整个就是一心脏病史
My family is the history of heart disease.
法国有处洞穴壁画
There's a cave painting in France
画的就是我一老祖宗在这样
of one of my ancestors doing this:
那这可能是遗传的咯
So it's probably genetic.
可能吧
Well, maybe.
妈妈还听到了些可能让她心烦的消息
Mom also had just gotten some news that might have upset her.
什么
What?
这不重要
It's not important.
说吧  霍华德  我将是你妻子
Come on, Howard, I'm going to be your wife.
你可以跟我分享任何事
You can share anything with me.
你这么想  但并不是的
You'd think that. But no.
你告诉她我们要结婚
You told her we were going to get married
然后她就心脏病发作了吗
and she had a heart attack?
你千万别多想
You can't take that personally.
那让她还能怎么想
How else is she supposed to take it?
你只要记住的是
What you've got to keep in mind is that
我爸去世后
ever since my dad left,
我就是我妈妈的整个世界
I've been the whole world to my mother.
她会觉得其他能做到她所不能的
I mean, she'd be threatened by any woman
任何女人  都是威胁
who can give me what she can't.
你是指性爱
You mean sexual intercourse?
你这么一说  就显得怪怪的
Well, when you say it like that you make it sound creepy.
怎么了
What happened?
霍华德妈妈心脏病发作
Howard's mother had a heart attack
是因为我跟他上床  而她自己不能
because I have sex with him and she can't.
妮妮  等等
Bernie, wait!
你载我回家  我就给你一千块
I'll give you $1,000 if you'll drive me home.
你能来医院看霍华德真好
Nice of you to come for Howard.
他是我朋友嘛  应该的
Well, he's my friend. It's what you do.
抱歉  怎么了
I'm sorry, did I miss something?
只是觉得怪怪的
It's just so weird.
霍华德·沃罗威茨是我朋友
Howard Wolowitz is my friend.
有次他想深吻我
You know, once he tried to stick his tongue down my throat
被我打破了鼻子
and I broke his nose.
这比他是你朋友更容易相信点
That's a little easier to believe than he's your friend.
是啊  谁说不是呢
Yeah, tell me about it.
我哥在印度有一大群像他一样的朋友
You know, my brother had a group of friends like this in India.
都穿紧身连衣裤戴护目镜
They dressed up in leotards and goggles
并自称"新德里恐龙战队"
and called themselves the New Delhi Power Rangers.
你是指他小时候吗
You mean when he was little.
没你想的那么小
Not as little as you'd want him to be.
这咖啡太难喝了
You know, this stuff is horrible.
想去找看看有没餐厅
You want to see if we can find the cafeteria
-买杯好咖啡吗  -当然
- and get real coffee? - Sure.
我们要去餐厅买咖啡
We're going to the cafeteria to get some coffee.
有人要吗
You want anything?
我不用了
I'm fine.
她们能合得来真好
That's nice that they're getting along.
你现任和前任女友一起玩
Your girlfriend and your ex-girlfriend are hanging out together?
没错  对你来说只可能是好事
Oh, yeah, that can only be good for you.
你什么意思啊
What are you talking about?
其中一位跟你分手了
One of them broke up with you.
你真想她告诉另一位为什么吗
Do you really want her telling the other one why?
无所谓
I don't care.
我又没什么藏着掖着
I don't have anything to hide.
很好  很好
Good, good.
那你就没什么好担心的了
Then you have nothing to worry about.
对  我一点不担心
No, I do not.
你这个卑鄙小人
You are a mean little man.
你这么以为是因为我父母并不爱我
You'd think it'd be because my parents didn't love me,
但事实上他们非常爱我
but actually they loved me a great deal.
妮妮  绝不是因为你
Bernie, it's not you.
那只是她自以为是
She's just set in her ways.
那我们还怎么能在一起  如果
How can we be together if the thought of us
我们结婚可能会害死你妈啊
getting married might kill your mother?
这就是生命的轮回啊  亲爱的
It's the circle of life, sweetie.
未来有天我们儿子结婚  会害死你
One day our son will marry someone and it will kill you.
霍华德  我得上洗手间
Howard, I have to go to the bathroom
但没人肯载我回家
and no one will take me home.
这里的洗手间怎么了
What's wrong with the bathroom here?
这里有肺炎球菌  链球菌  葡萄球菌
Pneumococcus, streptococcus, staphylococcus
和其他各种球菌
and other assorted coccuses.
谢尔顿  我妈生命垂危
Sheldon, my mother is on her deathbed
而我未婚妻正极度悲伤于害她入院
and my fiance is grief-stricken over putting her there.
我才不要载你回家
I'm not taking you home.
那你至少能陪我去厕所吗
Will you at least go with me to the restroom here,
好帮我开个门  冲个尿池
so you can open the door and flush the urinal?
不去
No!
现在或许是指出真理的最佳时期  霍华德
This might be a good time to point out, Howard,
友情在一定程度上是需要相互忍让的
that friendship requires a certain give and take.
先别关门
Hold the door.
沃罗威茨先生
Mr. Wolowitz?
-她还好吗  -您母亲不是心脏病突发
- Is she okay? - It wasn't a heart attack.
她现在醒了  在安稳地休息呢
She's awake, she's resting comfortably--
我们还在为她做身体检查
we're still running tests.
我可以进去看她吗
Can I see her?
其实她有吩咐  原话是这样的
Actually, she said, and I quote,
她想"先见那个天主教的小妞"
she'd "like to see the little Catholic girl first."
我  为什么是我
Me? Why me?
这个问题犹太人扪心自问了好几个世纪了
Jews have been asking that for centuries.
至今没什么好答案
There's no real good answer.
好吧  祝我好运
Okay, well, wish me luck.
别担心  没事的
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
先把十字架藏起来
Let's just hide Mr. Cross.
如果那玩意儿碰到她  会烧伤的
If it touches her, it burns.
-你带一个天主教的女孩回家见你妈  -是的
- You brought a Catholic girl home to your mother? - Yeah.
那我给你开点镇静剂吧
Why don't I write you a prescription for Xanax.
总是完事了
Finally.
隔离室
采用传染性疾病护理程序
这又是哪门子新玩意儿
Oh, what fresh hell is this?
等等  你不能离开这儿  你已经被感染了
Wait, you can't leave here, you've been exposed.
不  我没有
No, I haven't.
防护措施做得很好
It's all good.
你想聊极品老妈这个话题吗
You want to talk about crazy mothers,
莱纳德的妈妈对他没表示过半点的认可
Leonard's mom wouldn't give him any sort of approval growing up.
可怜的小家伙
Oh, the poor thing.
所以他才会这么渴望取悦女人
It makes him desperate to please women.
也正是他的小前戏耍不停的原因
That's why the foreplay goes on and on.
的确  对吧
It does, doesn't it?
他好像为了要获得奖励一样
It's like he's trying to win a prize.
佩妮贴心小建议  千万不要打瞌睡
A word of advice-- don't doze off.
不然你都听不见何时结束
You will never hear the end of it.
救我
Help me!
回来
Come back!
佩妮
Penny!
我跟佩妮一起做过一些事
There are a couple of things I did with Penny
听上去可能有点傻  但是
that might be a little silly, but...
比如
Like what?
偶尔  在我们上床前
Every once in a while, before we'd go to bed,
我会为她表演点小节目
I'd put on a little show for her.
你的"小节目"是指什么
What do you mean "a show"?
这个嘛  就是我脱衣服的方式
Well, you know, the way I took my clothes off.
比如伴着音乐
Like, to music?
如果没音乐  那我看起来不很傻啊
I'd look pretty stupid if there was no music.
那你跳的是脱衣舞咯
So you'd do a striptease?
我又不是抱着根钢管搔首弄姿
I wasn't swinging around a pole.
不错  不错
Good, good.
不过有次我往身上擦了闪粉
There was one time I put body glitter on.
我觉得你不必为了佩妮会不会
Well, I don't think you have to worry
把这事告诉我妹妹而担心
about Penny telling my sister that.
对  她不会说的
No, she wouldn't.
你的问题在我会不会告诉她
Your big problem is me telling her.
你还真是个卑鄙小人
You really are a mean little man.
天啊  的确如此
Oh, God, that's so true.
的确  我懂  对吧
Yeah, I know, right?
你们俩怎么去这么半天
Hey, what took you guys so long?
我们聊天来着
Oh, we were just chatting.
不错嘛  聊什么了
That's nice. What about?
我们只是对你的床上功夫
We were just comparing notes
交换下意见而已
about how you are in the sack.
-真有趣  -就是
- That's funny. - Yeah.
如果她不是在开玩笑呢
What if she wasn't kidding?
没关系
It doesn't matter.
哥可是前戏小王子
I'm the king of foreplay.
怎么样了
Hey, how'd it go?
你个2B
You're a putz.
你知道这是什么意思吗
You know what that means?
知道  你呢
Yeah. Do you?
你妈刚教我的
Your mother just taught it to me.
她觉得她在那家餐厅食物中毒了
She thinks she got food poisoning from that deli
想确认下我是否没事
and she just wanted to make sure I was okay.
那你有事吗
And are you?
有  因为我跟个2B订婚了
No, because I'm engaged to a putz.
你让我误信她心脏病发是因为我
You let me believe I was the reason she had a heart attack.
那是基于现有证据嘛
Well, based on the available evid--
闭嘴
Shut up!
你妈说我是个好女孩
She said I'm a wonderful girl
能娶到我是你的福气
and that you're lucky to have me.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
厕所
To the toilet!
你有意见啊
Is that okay with you?!
是我的错觉
Is it just me,
还是她生气的时候  声音是特别性感啊
or does she sound sexy when she's angry?
高山精灵
Mountain Elf.
这精灵不是高山的  是现成的
He takes the elf from off the shelf.
地狱猎犬
Hell Hounds.
地狱猎犬啊  谁把撒旦的狗放出来了
Hell Hounds-- who let the Satanic dogs out?
是谁  谁  谁
Who? Who-who?
神勇巨蟒
Colossal Serpent.
我裤裆里面也有条神勇的巨蟒
I got a colossal serpent right here.
你非得这样吗
Must you?
抱歉  我只是想让你高兴点
Sorry, I'm just trying to cheer my buddy up.
腐朽僵尸
Rotting Zombie.
谢尔顿校内新头像
Sheldon's new Facebook photo.
赞多  北方巫师
Zandor, Wizard of the North.
哈哈  我赢了
Ha! I win.
如果硬要省略掉
If you skip the part about being
你因为接触到致命疾病
under a two-week quarantine
而被隔离两周这件事
because you were exposed to a deadly disease,
我们甘拜下风
absolutely.